Pedro Alexandre Parreira Primor

Azeitão, Portugal

+351 961241116 | pedro.primor@pm.me | linkedin.com/in/pedroprimor/

ABOUT ME

Computer engineering student with a passion for solving data analytics problems by applying machine learning and data mining techniques. Currently enrolled at NOVA SST in Lisbon for the final year of my master's degree. Experience in front-end web development and mobile game development but open to expand my professional expertise to other fields of computer science. Focused on a computer engineering project on the optimization of the last-mile delivery step in the postal sector, in collaboration with CTT – Correios de Portugal, S.A..

EDUCATION

NOVA School of Science and Technology Integrated Master in Computer Engineering Technische Universität Dresden

Erasmus+ Programme Exchange Period

Lisbon, Portugal
Apr. 2021 – Oct. 2021
Dresden, Germany

Sep. 2017 – Present

Work experience

Front-end Developer and QA Assistant

Jul. 2019 – Aug. 2019 Lisbon, Portugal

Automatication

- Developed React components to display the result of some unit tests on a web page;
- Experimented with AWS Amplify's authentication mechanism;
- Learned to develop unit tests for JavaScript environments using JEST.

Front-end Developer Intern

Apr. 2020 – Jul. 2020

Altitude Software

Lisbon, Portugal

- Developed React components to replace existing ASP.NET components in a contact centers management platform;
- Integrated the components with the application's back-end using C# and ASP.NET.

PROJECTS

Optimization Problems in the Postal Sector | Python, CPLEX

Jan. 2022 – Present

- Operations research and data analytics project;
- Had the main goal of optimizing the last-mile delivery step of the postal distribution process;
- Explored how to model and solve a vehicle routing problem adapted to the postal sector, in general, and the company (CTT), in particular;
- Provided meaningful insight and visualizations about routing solutions with Tableau.

My Spelling Game | Unity, C#, SQLite

Jul. 2018 – Nov. 2018

• Developed and published a 2D mobile game for Android/iOS along with a graphic designer.

Volunteering

Kekri celebrations in North Karelia

Oct. 2022

Hyvärilä – Youth and Holiday Centre

Nurmes, Finland

• Met with local community members and organized various activities;

EVENTS

Unity Workshop - JORTEC Informática 2019 Unity, C#	Feb. 2019
Android Training Program Android Studio, Java, Kotlin	Nov. 2019
EUROPT Summer School 2022 Mathematical optimization, Game theory	Aug. 2022

LANGUAGES

Native: Portuguese Proficient: English

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, C#, SQL, Cypher, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Kotlin, Go, Rust

Frameworks: React, Redux, Flutter

Developer tools: Git, webpack, npm, VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Android Studio, Unity

Libraries: Material-UI, pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, scikit-learn, OpenCV

Sofware packages: Tableau, CPLEX